Guide to the Linda Wu and Janita Gee records of the Gee family in Houston, 1955-2011 MS 878
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Linda Wu and Janita Gee records of the Gee family in Houston
1955-2011
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Gee family
MS 878
4 Linear Feet 4 boxes (2 of plaques / memorabilia, 1 of documents, one of oversize photos and proclamations)
This collection includes sources which document Gee restaurants and/or events, the family of Jane and Albert Gee, and activities of the Chinese American Citizens Alliance (Houston Chapter). Formats include photos (circa 75), letters, plaques, awards, certificates, newspaper clippings, magazine clippings, brochures, pamphlets.
Biographical / Historical
The Gee family first rose to prominence with C.B. Albert Gee (b. 1920) and his success in the Houston restaurant business. He began working in the industry in 1936, first as an assistant to his uncle Harry Gee, Sr., before opening up restaurants of his own, such as Gee's Kitchen, the Frying Pan, and the Ding How—the latter of which was his first large restaurant. He went on to establish the PolyAsian Restaurants, where Cantonese, Japanese, and Polynesian foods were served. He helped pioneer Chinese take out with the Chinese Oven and Hong Kong Chef restaurants. He served as president of the Houston Restaurant Association from 1961-62 as well as president of the Houston Lodge of the Chinese American Citizens Alliance (CACA), which he helped to found. For the first hundred years or so of CACA's history (founded in 1895), he was the only person not from California to ever serve as the CACA National Grand President. The records in this collection—documenting Albert Gee's recognition in CACA, the Houston community, and the nation—come from his two daughters, Linda Wu and Janita Gee. Wu graduated from the University of Texas, Austin with a degree in fashion merchandising, working in retailing with Joske's of Texas before becoming a real estate broker; she eventually retired, remaining active in Houston's Asian American community and serving as CACA president in 2011. Gee graduated from Texas Christian University and got her master's from San Francisco State College before working as head of the science department at Moreau Catholic High School in Hayward, California.
Content Description
This collection includes sources which document Gee restaurants and/or events, the family of Jane and Albert Gee, and activities of the Chinese American Citizens Alliance (Houston Chapter). Formats include photos (circa 75), letters, plaques, awards, certificates, newspaper clippings, magazine clippings, brochures, pamphlets.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Linda Wu and Janita Gee records of the Gee family in Houston, 1955-2011, MS 878, Woodson Research Center, Fondren Library, Rice University
Index Terms
Subjects
Asian Americans; Business
Document Types
photographs; clippings (information artifacts); awards; brochures; family papers
Places
Texas -- Houston
Subjects (Persons)
Wu, Linda; Gee, Albert; Gee, Janita
- Series I: Documents and photographs
  - Letters and correspondence, 1961-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of CACA and Gee Family events, 1957-1976 and undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    Including Albert Gee, Jane Gee, Linda Gee, Janita Gee, Hong Kong Chef (Bellaire restaurant), Hugh O'Bryan,Connie Chng, Kim sisters (Korean musical act), Gordon McRae, Jack Chow, and others unidentified.
  - Gee family magazine and newspaper clippings, 1955-1980 and undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - CACA programs and publications, 1956-1995 and undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Brochures and programs, 1958-1976 and undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Albert Gee biographical sketch, written 1998, and business card (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Copy of Senate resolution 201 (senatorial apology for the Chinese Exclusion Act), 2011 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series II: Awards
  - Awards and certificates, 1962-2011 and undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Plaque: Gee Family Association Hall of Fae, Albert C.B. Gee, 1994 (Box 1, Envelope 9)
  - Gavel: Albert Gee, President 1956, CACA Houston Lodge (Box 1, Envelope 10)
  - Gavel: Albert Gee, Outstanding Leadership, President 1956, CACA Houston Lodge, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Envelope 11)
  - Plaque: Albert Gee, Outstanding and Dedicated Service, CACA, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Gavel: Jane Gee, HRS Auxilliary, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Envelope 13)
  - Lucite medal: Albert Gee for International Understanding, Houston International Trade and Travel Fair, 1960 (Box 1, Envelope 14)
  - Plaque: Jane Gee, Chairperson, Miss Chinatown Houston Pageant, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Gavel on plaque: Jane Gee, Outstanding Leadership and Accomplishment, CACA Houston, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Series III: Oversize documents, photographs, and awards
  - Texas State Legislature gavel honoring House Resolution 1742 for CACA National Convention (Box 2, Folder -)
  - Chinese language documents (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Proclamation, Jane Eng Gee Day 2003 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Resolution for Albert Gee's election as CACA President (national), by Mayor Louis Welch, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Plaque: Jane Gee, first woman president of CACA Houston Lodge, 1993 (Box 3, Folder -)